balls.ie 2019-12-19

# Privacy Policy | Balls.ie

**Privacy Policy for www.balls.ie**

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at thegaffer@balls.ie.

At www.balls.ie, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by www.balls.ie and how it is used.

**Log Files**

Like many other Web sites, www.balls.ie makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

## Cookies and Web Beacons

www.balls.ie does use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.

## Cookies

Balls.ie use a number of different cookies on our site. If you do not know what cookies are, or how to control or delete them, then we recommend you visit [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) for detailed guidance.

The list below describe the cookies we use on this site and what we use them for. Currently we operate an ‘implied consent’ policy which means that we assume you are happy with this usage. If you are not happy, then you should either not use this site, or you should delete the cookies having visited the site, or you should browse the site using your browser’s anonymous usage setting (called “Incognito” in Chrome, “InPrivate” for Internet Explorer, “Private Browsing” in Firefox and Safari etc.)

## _First Party Cookies_

These are cookies that are set by this website directly.

**Google Analytics and **Comscore  **:** We use Google Analytics to collect information about visitor behaviour on our website. Google Analytics stores information about what pages you visit, how long you are on the site, how you got here and what you click on. This Analytics data is collected via a JavaScript tag in the pages of our site and is not tied to personally identifiable information.We therefore do not collect or store your personal information (e.g. your name or address) so this information cannot be used to identify who you are.

You can find out more about Google’s position on privacy as regards its analytics service at [http://www.google.com/intl/en_uk/analytics/privacyoverview.html](https://www.google.com/intl/en_uk/analytics/privacyoverview.html)

**WordPress:**  Our websites runs the popular WordPress CMS and cookies are used to store basic data on your interactions with WordPress, and whether you have logged into WordPress. We use a  **session cookie**  to remember your log-in for you if you are a registered user and we deem these as being strictly necessary to the working of the website. If these are disabled then various functionality on the site will be broken.

More information on session cookies and what they are used for at <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/session-cookies-used-for.html>

## _Third Party Cookies_

These are cookies set on your machine by external websites whose services are used on this site. Cookies of this type are the sharing buttons across the site allow visitors to share content onto social networks. Cookies are currently set by  ****LinkedIn, Twitter, Facebook, Google+ and Pinterest**. In order to implement these buttons, and connect them to the relevant social networks and external sites, there are scripts from domains outside of our website. You should be aware that these sites are likely to be collecting information about what you are doing all around the internet, including on this website.

**DoubleClick DART Cookie**

.:: Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on www.balls.ie.

.:: Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to www.balls.ie and other sites on the Internet.

.:: Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL - http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include ....

Google Adsense

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on www.balls.ie send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

www.balls.ie has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. www.balls.ie's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites.
